<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tmux on ErebusBat</title>
    <link>http://www.erebusbat.com/tags/tmux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tmux on ErebusBat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 09:42:56 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.erebusbat.com/tags/tmux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>TMUX Login Wrapper Script</title>
      <link>http://www.erebusbat.com/2015/08/tmux-login-wrapper-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 09:42:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.erebusbat.com/2015/08/tmux-login-wrapper-script/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After watching a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5r6yzFEXajQ&#34;&gt;talk on Vim &amp;amp; TMUX&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nicknisi&#34;&gt;Nick Nisi&lt;/a&gt; I was inspired to improve on his &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nicknisi/dotfiles/blob/master/bin/tm&#34;&gt;tm script&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Nick&amp;rsquo;s original, my script allows me to easily attach to running tmux sessions and create ad hoc new onces. I then added the ability to list any &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tmuxinator/tmuxinator&#34;&gt;tmuxinator&lt;/a&gt; configurations I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted a workflow where I could easily connect to existing tmux sessions, which Nick&amp;rsquo;s script did great.  However I am already a heavy Tmuxinator user and have several pre-defined configurations (as you can see).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example gif video below you can see the general idea in action (forgive the horrid colors, that is another issue I am working on):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.erebusbat.com/img/2015/201508-tmlogin.gif&#34; alt=&#34;gif&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;login-shell:1d7a3107e57203900f6e4fc32eccbfc8&#34;&gt;Login Shell&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did set this up as my login shell, why?  Well with my current ZSH config it can take a second or two for my prompt to load.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to track down why that is happening.  After my sessions are loaded then I am not spinning up that many shells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However waiting on my slow shell session startup just to turn around and launch tmux to launch more ZSH seemed like a waste. By setting &lt;code&gt;tmlogin&lt;/code&gt; as my login shell it spins up instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This did cause some minor problems, given that &lt;code&gt;tmlogin&lt;/code&gt; is really not a shell.  Exporting my real shell in &lt;code&gt;tmlogin&lt;/code&gt; seems to have fixed that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find it useful then please drop me a line, it is dirty and hacked together, but it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/ErebusBat/dacc0bcd92d7aa1494f1&#34;&gt;the gist here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>